Krushna Shete

+91 7774892221 | krushnashete2001@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub

Profile

Data Engineer with 2+ years of experience in building large-scale data pipelines, ETL processes, and data warehouse solutions. Utilized technologies like Python, SQL, Spark and AWS to develop multi-terabyte scalable big data solutions for Banking Domain.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL

Big Data Technologies: Spark, PySpark, Spark SQL Streaming Technology: Kafka, Spark structured streaming

Amazon S3, AWS Glue, AWS EMR, AWS Redshift, Amazon RDS, Amazon Kinesis Cloud computing:

Data Engineering Tools: Data Modelling, ETL/ELT data Pipeline, Dbt (Data build tool)

Orchestration: Airflow, Github

Familiar: Linux, Kubernetes, PowerBI, dbt

Experience

Tata consultancy services

March 2024 - Present

Data Engineer Pune, India

- Redesigned and optimized ETL pipelines in PySpark and SQL for loan and compliance datasets, improving pipeline performance by 35% and reducing data load failures.
- Implemented AWS-based data ingestion workflows (S3, Glue, Redshift) to manage regulatory and audit datasets, increasing data processing efficiency.
- Integrated and processed billing data from multiple sources including AWS, Azure, GCP, and Oracle, handling various file formats like JSON, CSV, and Parquet.
- Implemented Medallion Architecture and Delta Lake for data reliability, resulting in 10% faster queries and enhanced data consistency across all environments.

Mahindra Sona

September 2024 - March 2024

Data Analyst Nashik. India

- Analyzed and visualized data using Excel, Power BI, and SQL to identify trends and optimize processes.
- Designed and optimised SQL queries to generate reports on these policies which were used for deciding premium, calculation of billing information, etc
- · Collaborated with Business Analysts and prospective clients for Requirement gathering, gaining feedback and understanding the business logic.
- Extensively used Excel for data analysis along with querying of data using SQL for data analysis hence finding data gaps, data ambiguity, data duplication and data filtering.

EDUCATION

SPPU University

Bachelor of Engineering

Pune, Maharashtra July 2020 - June 2023

K.K.Wagh college of Diploma

Nashik, Maharashtra

Senior Secondary School

April 2017 - Mar 2020